dot files set up or restore a fully customized development environment by
dot 文件通过维护基于文本的配置文件的存储库来设置或恢复完全定制的开发环境，
maintaining a repository of text-based config files
as developers were trained to write dry code do not repeat yourself
因为开发人员接受过编写干代码的培训不要重复自己，
but this principle also applies to other areas of a developer's life like the
但这一原则也适用于开发人员生活的其他领域，例如
configuration of a development environment
配置 开发环境
imagine this you spent months fine tuning your top of the line intel mac
想象一下，你花了几个月的时间来微调你的顶级英特尔 mac，
but now need to throw it in the garbage because the new mac mini with an m1 chip
但现在需要把它扔进垃圾箱，因为带有 m1 芯片的新 mac mini
will blow it out of the water are you going to reinstall and reconfigure
会把它从水中吹出来你要重新安装和重新配置
everything from scratch hopefully not dot files are those little
所有东西吗？ 从头开始希望不是点文件是
hidden files on your system that start with a period
系统上那些以
like bashprofile.env or git config just to name a few with a repository of
bashprofile.env 或 git config 之类的句点开头的小隐藏文件，仅举几例，这些文件的存储库
these files you can chronicle the installation of your favorite
可以记录您喜欢的
applications and command line tools keep track of how all that software is
应用程序和命令行工具的安装跟踪所有软件的
configured and record all the various system preferences
配置方式并记录
and changes that you've made to your computer these files already live on
您对 com 所做的所有各种系统偏好和更改假设这些文件已经存在于
your system and when you harness their power you can replicate your perfect
您的系统中，当您利用它们的强大功能时，您可以
development environment on a new computer in a
在新计算机上复制完美的开发环境，以
completely hands-off and automated way to get started you'll want to organize
完全不干涉和自动化的方式开始您需要将
all of your configuration files in a git repository
所有配置文件组织在一个 git存储库
that will allow you to track changes and clone the repo on other machines
，可让您跟踪更改并在其他机器上克隆 repo
its code will contain at least one script that applies or installs the
它的代码将包含至少一个脚本，
configurations on a new system and that means weeks of hard manual
用于在新系统上应用或安装配置，这意味着可以将数周的艰苦
labor can be reduced down to a git clone followed by an install script
体力劳动减少到 git clone然后是一个安装脚本，
maintaining your own dot files repo will help you develop discipline for other
维护您自己的点文件 repo 将帮助您培养其他
important skills from command line use to get to the
重要技能的纪律，从命令行使用到
organization and inner workings of your machine wax
您的机器蜡的组织和内部工作
on wax off read if you're ready to learn
如果您准备好了解
more and build your own dot files repo stay tuned today we're going
更多信息和构建，请阅读 您自己的点文件存储库今天继续关注我们将
beyond 100 seconds with special guest patrick mcdonald he's the instructor of
与特邀嘉宾 patrick mcdonald 一起超越 100 秒，他
a full dot files course and will teach you how to set up your
是完整点文件课程的讲师，并且 w 我会教你如何逐步设置
own dot files repo step by step taking your developer productivity to
自己的 dot 文件 repo将你的开发人员生产力提升
the next level youtube meet patrick over the last 20 plus years
到一个新的水平 youtube在过去的 20 多年里遇见 patrick
i've set up enough computers to have acquired an appreciation of automating
我已经设置了足够的计算机来获得对自动化
that process and i've gathered a few tricks i'd like
该过程的欣赏 '已经收集了一些技巧，我想
to share with you hello everyone i'm patrick and i'll be your guide as we
与你分享大家好，我是 patrick，我将成为你的向导，因为
go beyond 100 seconds to learn how to back up a few typical
我们超过 100 秒来学习如何备份一些典型的
dot files without disturbing your computer's
dot 文件，而不会影响你的计算机的
ability to use those files to configure software
能力
if you've never heard of dot files you're probably familiar with a home
如果您从未听说过点文件，请使用这些文件来配置软件，您可能熟悉
directory that looks like this but as jeff mentioned mac os is littered
看起来像这样的主目录，但正如 jeff 提到的，mac os 充满
with hidden files vs code is open to the same home
了隐藏文件，而代码对同一个主
directory and its file explorer shows several more items we can tell
目录及其 文件资源管理器显示了更多项目，我们可以告诉
finder to show the same hidden files by entering the key combination command
finder 通过输入组合键命令来显示相同的隐藏文件 shift
shift period most hidden files have a dot prefix
period 大数隐藏文件都有一个点前缀，因此
hence the name dot files they can be folders as well as
名称点文件它们可以是文件夹以及 文件
files and in special cases they can be hidden
，在特殊情况下，它们可以
by the operating system even though they are missing the dot
被操作系统隐藏，即使它们缺少
that's all we need to know about finder so let's look at vs code where we
我们需要知道的关于 finder 的所有点，所以让我们看看 vs 代码，我们
can see that our system uses dot files in our
可以看到我们的系统在我们的
home directory software that comes pre-installed uses
主目录软件中使用了点文件 预装也使用
hidden files too and so does the custom software that we
隐藏文件，
install on our own if you've been using your computer for a
如果您已经使用计算机很
significant amount of time you likely have many more dot files here
长时间，我们自己安装的自定义软件也会使用隐藏文件，您可能有更多的点文件在这里
we are going to focus on these two at the bottom git config
我们将重点关注这两个在底部 git config
and zshrc when you started using git you probably issued a pair of commands
和 zshrc 当您开始使用 git 时，您可能发出了一对命令
to set your name and email address those settings ended
来设置您的姓名和电子邮件地址，随着您继续学习和使用 git，这些设置最终会
up here in the git config file as you continue learning and using
出现在 git config文件中，
git this file can grow with more
这个文件可以随着更多
configurations before we move on let me recommend using
配置而增长在我们继续之前，让我建议
the no reply email address available with your github account
when you publish your dot files repo for the world to see
您在发布您的 dot 文件 repo 时使用您的 github 帐户中可用的无回复电子邮件地址，以便全世界看到
this lets you keep your personal email address a secret
这可以让您保留您的个人电子邮件 邮件地址 a secret
zsh is the new default shell on mac os and the zshrc file is what you use to
zsh 是 mac os 上的新默认 shell，zshrc 文件是您用来自
customize the shell experience so far we are only using this to
定义 shell 体验的文件到目前为止，我们仅使用它来自
customize the prompt but like we saw with the git config file
定义提示，但就像我们看到的 git config 文件一样，
we can add to this file in many ways we already have two files that are going
我们可以添加到 这个文件在很多方面我们已经有两个文件会
to change over time what does this mean yes it means we're
随着时间而改变这是什么意思是的这意味着我们
going to need a git repository to start tracking these files along with the
将需要一个 git 存储库来开始跟踪这些文件以及
changes we make to them let's open the integrated terminal where
我们对它们所做的更改让我们打开集成 终端，
we can see our super fancy custom prompt in action
我们可以看到我们的超级花哨的自定义提示正在运行
and where we can see that we start off in the home directory
，我们可以看到我们从主目录开始
i've already set up a repository on github so i'll start a git clone command
我已经在 github 上设置了一个存储库，所以我将启动一个 git clone 命令
and paste in the ssh url now we need to tell it the directory to create
并粘贴 ssh url 现在我们需要告诉它要创建的目录
and since everybody else is doing it let's make a hidden folder by prefixing
，因为其他人都在这样做，所以让我们通过在
our dot files repo with a period our new directory has a
我们的 dot 文件 repo 前加上句点来创建一个隐藏文件夹，我们的新目录有一个
readme that we will look at shortly but let's start by moving these two dot
自述文件，我们很快就会看到，但让我们从移动这两个开始 d  ot
files into the repo so we can back them up of course the act
文件到 repo 中，所以我们可以备份它们当然移动它们的行为
of moving them isn't enough and these two files are
是不够的，这两个文件仍然没有被
still untracked so we will cd into the dot files
跟踪，所以我们将 cd 进入 dot files
directory where we can add the two files to the
目录，我们可以将这两个文件添加到
repository and then we will commit them but is this all we have to do will we be
存储库，然后 我们将提交它们，但这就是我们所
done after entering this command let's try it and it looks like we have a
要做的，在输入此命令后我们是否完成让我们尝试一下，看起来我们遇到了
problem instead of using the user information
问题，而不是使用
that we just saw in our git config the output says that git automatically
我们刚刚在 git config 中看到的用户信息，输出显示 git 根据用户名和主机名自动
configured this committer information based on the
配置此提交者信息
username and hostname remember that software likes to use our
请记住，软件喜欢使用我们的
home directory so by moving this file to a different
主目录，因此通过将此文件移动到不同的
location we've broken the configuration every time we make a commit git will
位置，我们每次提交时都会破坏配置 git 会
remind us of this problem let's copy this suggested command about
提醒我们这个问题让我们复制 这个关于
resetting the author and amending the commit and we will try
重置作者和修改提交的建议命令，我们将
to fix this in a few minutes what about our zsh configurations i
在几分钟内尝试修复这个问题，我们的 zsh 配置我
think we can assume that these are broken as well
认为我们可以假设这些被破坏为
keep an eye on the file explorer to the left as i kill this terminal
请注意左侧的文件资源管理器，因为我
when a shell session ends its command history is written out
在 shell 会话结束时杀死了这个终端，它的命令历史记录被写出，
and as software continues to add files to our home directory
并且随着软件继续将文件添加到我们的主目录，
we have to decide whether to move these files to our repository
我们必须决定是否将这些文件移动到我们的存储库
zsh history is not the type of file we want to track in our repo
zsh 历史记录不是我们想要在我们的 repo 中跟踪的文件类型，
so we will leave it here in the home directory we just saw that zsh
所以我们将把它留在主目录中，我们刚刚看到 zsh
writes to our home directory but it tries to read from it as well
写入我们的主目录，但是
if we open a new shell we see that we've lost our custom prompt
如果我们打开一个新的 shell，它也会尝试从中读取 我们看到我们丢失了自定义提示，
because zsh could not find the zshrc file
因为 zsh 找不到 zshrc文件，
instead we see the default prompt which happens to have
而是看到了默认提示，它恰好
a similar default to the one we just saw for git using the same username and
与我们刚刚看到的使用相同用户名和
hostname combination how do we fix these broken
主机名组合的 git 的默认提示相似我们如何修复 这些损坏的
configurations we don't want to duplicate these files
配置我们不想复制这些文件
store their copies in the home directory and manually keep them in sync
将它们的副本存储在主目录中并手动使它们保持同步
luckily there's a way that a file can be in two places at the same time
幸运的是有一种方法可以使文件同时位于两个位置，
which is called a symbolic link or symlink for short
这称为符号 c链接或符号链接
to create one we will use the ln or link command
简称创建一个我们将使用ln或链接命令
then we will add the s option which stands for symbolic link
然后我们将添加代表符号链接的s选项
now we'll pass in the full path to the real file in our dot files directory
现在我们将在我们的点文件目录中传递到真实文件的完整路径
and lastly we'll pass in the path to the original location
最后我们 '将传递
where the zshrc file is expected to live the file explorer now shows that the
到zshrc文件预期存在的原始位置的路径文件资源管理器现在显示
zshrc file is back in the home directory but it has an arrow to the right which
zshrc文件回到主目录但它有一个向右的箭头
signifies that this is a sim link if that arrow does not show up for you
表示这是一个sim链接如果 那个箭头没有出现，因为你
reload the window and it should appear now i'll kill the terminal again and
重新加载窗口，它
open the new simlink version from the home directory
to the right of the zshrc file in our dot files directory they
both look like normal files don't they but if i add a comment to the
现在应该出现了 文件不是，但是如果我向真实文件添加注释
real file and save it we can see that changes to
并保存它，我们可以看到
the real file at the left will show up in the symlink version at
左侧真实文件的更改将显示在右侧的符号链接版本中
the right of course we can delete these lines from the right
，当然我们可以从右侧删除这些行
and after another save those changes are reflected at the left
然后又保存了那些 c  hanges反映在左侧，
since vs code can follow the sim link to the real file
因为 vs 代码可以跟随 sim 链接到真实文件
and treat it as a real file i bet zsh can too
并将其视为真实文件我敢打赌 zsh也可以，
if we open a new shell we see our custom prompt has returned
如果我们打开一个新的 shell，我们会看到我们的自定义提示
when a shell loads it looks for the zshrc file in the home directory
在 shell 加载时返回它寻找主目录中的 zshrc 文件
which follows the sim link to the real file and
跟随 sim 链接到真实文件，
the customization makes it into the shell not only did the shell load the
并且自定义使其进入shell 不仅 shell 加载了
zshrc file it also loaded the zsh history file
zshrc 文件，它还加载了
which is still in the home directory this means we have access to previous
仍然在主目录中的 zsh 历史文件这意味着我们 可以访问以前的
commands i can press up to retrieve the most recent command
命令，我可以按向上键从历史记录中检索最新的命令
from the history and then alter it to create a sim link
，然后更改它以创建
for the git config file which we see appear in the explorer with
git 配置文件的 sim 链接，我们看到该文件出现在资源管理器中，带有
another arrow icon we've seen enough of the home directory
另一个箭头图标，我们已经看到了足够的 主目录，
so before testing our git config fix let's open only the dot files directory
所以在测试我们的 git config 修复之前，让我们只打开点文件
the key combo we used in finder to show hidden files
目录我们在 finder 中使用的组合键来显示隐藏文件
command shift period works here as well of course the arrows here on the file
命令转换周期在这里也有效，当然文件图标上的箭头
icons mean the same thing they do in the file
表示 他们
explorer after opening the dot files directory we have less clutter to look
在打开点文件目录后在文件资源管理器中执行的操作相同，因为我们在 vs 代码中打开了点文件目录，所以我们看不到杂乱，
at since we have the dot files directory
open in vs code the integrated terminal will start at
the same location when we fire up a new shell
当我们启动新的 shell 时，集成终端将在同一位置启动
a git log command will remind us that our last commit has the wrong author
git log 命令会提醒我们上次提交的作者错误
which happened because we moved the git config file
，这是因为我们移动了 git配置文件，
we can check to see if our second sim link is working
我们可以通过检查显示正确 no 的电子邮件地址的全局 git config 来检查我们的第二个 sim链接是否有效
by checking the global git config for the email address
which shows the correct no reply email address that we saw before
回复我们之前看到的电子邮件地址，
now i'll paste in the command that i copied a bit ago
if you issue this command as is you'll end up editing the commit in vim
如果您按原样发出此命令，我将粘贴我刚才复制的命令，您最终将在 vim 中编辑提交，
because it is the default editor and if you're like me it will take you half an
因为它是默认编辑器，如果您喜欢 我需要
hour to figure out how to exit them changing the default editor perhaps to
半个小时才能弄清楚如何退出它们将默认编辑器更改为
nano or vs code is the type of configuration you could
nano 或 vs 代码是您
make to your git config file and the change would be tracked in
可以对 git 配置文件进行的配置类型，并且更改将在
your repo but in this case we don't actually want to edit the
您的存储库中进行跟踪，但是 在这种情况下，我们实际上并不想编辑
contents of the commit so we can add the no edit option another
提交的内容，因此我们可以添加 no edit 选项 再次
look at the git log shows that the author information
查看 git日志显示作者信息
has been corrected we have successfully backed up our
已更正，我们已成功备份
configurations while preserving the ability to use them
配置，同时保留了以下功能 使用它们，
but that won't do a lot of good if our software is not installed
但如果我们的软件没有安装，那不会有很大的好处
we need an automated way of installing software and for that we will use a
我们需要一种自动安装软件的方式，为此我们将使用一个
package manager called homebrew it just so happens that i used homebrew
名为 homebrew 的包管理器，碰巧我使用 homebrew
to install vs code along with some other software
来安装 vs code 对于其他一些软件，
we don't have time to learn much about it but homebrew keeps track of what it
我们没有时间了解太多，但是自制软件会跟踪它
has installed and can output a list of software with
已安装的内容，并且可以
this command after brew bundle dump i'll add the
在 brew bundle dump 后使用此命令输出软件列表我将添加
describe option for a little more info this command will create a file in your
描述选项以获取更多信息此命令将在您的当前目录中创建一个文件，
current directory so it's important that we are already in
因此重要的是我们已经在
our dot files repo our new brew file has a list of software
我们的点文件 repo我们的新 brew 文件有一个
that can be reinstalled at a later date taps are the repositories where homebrew
可以在以后重新安装的软件列表点击是 homebrew
keeps its own software along with the information about the
保存自己的软件以及
other software it can install brews are tools you typically use in
它可以安装的其他软件的信息的存储库brews 是您通常在 shell 中使用的工具
your shell these top two are new tools i've added
这前两个是我添加的新工具，
to improve my shell experience while these bottom two are upgraded
以改善我的 shell 体验，而后两个是升级
versions of pre-installed software so homebrew helps keep
版本 预安装的软件，因此 homebrew 有助于保持
everything up to date and the casks at the bottom are
一切都是最新的，底部的木桶是
full-blown applications that you probably recognize
成熟的应用程序，你可能已经认出了
let's start one last shell add the brew file to start tracking it
让我们启动最后一个 shell 添加 brew文件以开始跟踪它
and do another commit note that this time we did not get the warning message
并做另一个提交记录，这次我们做了 没有收到
that we saw before about automatically configuring the
我们之前看到的关于自动配置
author that's another sign that our git config sim link is working
作者的警告消息，这是我们的 gitconfig sim 链接正在工作的另一个迹象，
so we will push our changes to the remote repository
所以我们将把我们的更改推送到远程存储库，
now we've saved our software along with some configurations
现在我们已经保存了我们的软件和一些配置，
but we haven't recorded the process when the time comes to bootstrap a new
但我们还没有 t 记录了
computer using our dot files repository we are
使用我们的点文件存储库引导新计算机时的过程，我们
likely to forget some steps instead of researching and relearning
可能会忘记一些步骤inst 在研究和重新学习
these things we can keep a list in the readme
这些东西之前，我们可以在自述文件中保留一个列表
we haven't seen this first step yet before we can use git
我们还没有看到这第一步在我们可以使用 git
and homebrew we would need to install the command line tools
和 homebrew 之前我们需要安装命令行工具
after that we would clone the repository to our new machine
之后我们会将存储库克隆到我们的新 机器
ssh is preferred but you might want to start with
ssh 是首选，但您可能希望从 https 开始，
https and switch remotes after you've had a chance to set up ssh
并在您有机会
with our configuration files on our machine
在我们的机器上使用我们的配置文件设置 ssh 后切换遥控器，
we would then repeat our sim linking steps you can probably see that this
然后我们将重复我们的 sim 链接步骤，您可能会发现这
would be unwieldy if we had a dozen sim links
会很笨拙 如果我们有十几个 sim链接，
and the more manual steps we have the more error prone our process
并且手动步骤越多，我们的过程就越容易出错，
there are better ways to do this and this is the type of thing you'd
那么就有更好的方法来做到这一点，这就是你
eventually work into an install script finally we would install homebrew and
最终会在安装脚本中工作的类型，最后我们会安装 homebrew，
then point it to our brew file to reinstall
然后 将它指向我们的 brew 文件以重新安装
all of our software i really wish we had the time to see this step in action
我们所有的软件 我真的希望我们有时间看到这一步的实际操作，
because it is very satisfying just like we saw in the git config and
因为它非常令人满意，就像我们在 git config 和
zshrc files here we have another list of ideas
zshrc 文件中看到的一样，我们有一个
regarding improving our dot files process
关于改进我们的点文件过程的其他想法列表
we haven't looked at saving system preferences organizing this repo
我们没有考虑保存系统首选项将此存储库组织
into separate files building that install script
到单独的文件中构建安装脚本
or automating any of the steps we did there are 11 billion possibilities which
或自动化我们所做的任何步骤有 110 亿种可能性
we can't cover in 10 minutes let alone 100 seconds but as jeff
我们无法在 10 中涵盖 分钟，更不用说 100 秒，但正如杰夫
mentioned i have a growing course that thoroughly covers this
所说，我有一个不断增长的课程，可以彻底涵盖这些
material and for the next 30 days i'll keep the price
材料，在接下来的 30 天里，我将把价格
as low as the course platform allows enroll now and your next computer setup
保持在课程平台允许的最低价格现在注册，你的下一台计算机设置
will be no match for your dot file skills
将无法匹配 您的点文件技能
thank you for watching and since there's no way i could possibly thank jeff
感谢您的收看，因为我无法感谢杰夫
enough for sharing his stage with me please thank him on my behalf by liking
与我分享他的舞台，请通过喜欢
and sharing his videos subscribing to this channel and going
和分享他的视频来代表我感谢他订阅这个频道并成为
pro at fire ship io thanks for watching and
fire ship io 的专业人士，谢谢 看，
i will see you in the next one
我会在下一个见到你